Guide to the Theobald Wilson photographs 2013.005
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Series 1: Commercial photographs, 1976-2011; 5.3 Linear Feet in twenty nine binders, twelve folders, five oversize folders, and one oversize print; 12.2 Gigabytes in 9,618 files
  - Sanctified Learning Center, 2009/01/16 (Disk Digital files)
  - Maurice (Morris) Dixon 90th birthday party, 2009/01/31 (Binder 10)
  - Maurice (Morris) Dixon 90th birthday party, 2009/01/31 (Disk Digital files)
  - Armita Lord at Berean Baptist Church, 2009/02/22 (Binder 9)
  - Armita Lord at Berean Baptist Church, 2009/02/22 (Disk Digital files)
  - Black History Month - Brooklyn Borough Hall, 2009/02/26 (Binder 5)
  - Black History Month - Brooklyn Borough Hall, 2009/02/26 (Disk Digital files)
  - Dee's Safe Haven Learning Center, 2009/03/16 (Binder 9)
  - Dee's Safe Haven Learning Center, 2009/03/16 (Disk Digital files)
  - People's Cathedral (St. Michael and All Ages) Memorial for Bishop Heron Sam, 2009/05/31 (Binder 10)
  - People's Cathedral (St. Michael and All Ages) Memorial for Bishop Heron Sam, 2009/05/31 (Disk Digital files)
  - The Good Shepherd United Reformed Episcopal Church - Celebration of Father's Day - Rev. Eugene Phipps, 2009/06/21 (Binder 5)
  - The Good Shepherd United Reformed Episcopal Church - Celebration of Father's Day - Rev. Eugene Phipps, 2009/06/21 (Disk Digital files)
  - Steve and Sharon Bailey's barbecue, 2009/08/08 (Binder 5)
  - Steve and Sharon Bailey's barbecue, 2009/08/08 (Disk Digital files)
  - Dorothy's 90th Birthday. Maccine and Calvin Carter's barbeque, 2009/09/05 (Binder 5)
  - Dorothy's 90th Birthday. Maccine and Calvin Carter's barbeque, 2009/09/05 (Disk Digital files)
  - Arlene Punnett's Lodge - Installation as Worthy Grand Matron, 2009/09/13 (Binder 26)
  - Arlene Punnett's Lodge - Installation as Worthy Grand Matron, 2009/09/13 (Disk Digital files)
  - Cornerstone Baptist Church Business and Professional Women's luncheon, 2009/09/26 (Binder 9)
  - Cornerstone Baptist Church Business and Professional Women's luncheon, 2009/09/26 (Disk Digital files)
  - People's Cathedral part 1, 2009/09/27 (Binder 11)
  - People's Cathedral part 1, 2009/09/27 (Disk Digital files)
  - Bishops' High School Alumni Association 20th Anniversary Commemoration Service (Church of St. Mark), 2009/10/04 (Binder 11)
  - Bishops' High School Alumni Association 20th Anniversary Commemoration Service (Church of St. Mark), 2009/10/04 (Disk Digital files)
  - St. Mark Renewal of Marriage Vows service, 2009/10/11 (Binder 11)
  - St. Mark Renewal of Marriage Vows service, 2009/10/11 (Disk Digital files)
  - Church Women United 33rd Luncheon, 2009/10/24 (Binder 3)
  - Church Women United 33rd Luncheon, 2009/10/24 (Disk Digital files)
  - Ben Hur District Grand Mechanic Lodge #1 (65 Putnam Avenue), 2009/11/27 (Binder 11)
  - Ben Hur District Grand Mechanic Lodge #1 (65 Putnam Avenue), 2009/11/27 (Disk Digital files)
  - Bishop John Holder of Barbados at St. Marks, 2010/05/02 (Binder 11)
  - Bishop John Holder of Barbados at St. Marks, 2010/05/02 (Disk Digital files)
  - St. Mark's Mother's Union, 2010/06/10 (Binder 21)
  - St. Mark's Mother's Union, 2010/06/10 (Disk Digital files)
  - St. Mark Jurnol Groups with Wendy Nelbitt, 2010/09/19 (Binder 24)
  - St. Mark Jurnol Groups with Wendy Nelbitt, 2010/09/19 (Disk Digital files)
  - Mavis' 90th Birthday, 2010/10/10 (Binder 24)
  - Mavis' 90th Birthday, 2010/10/10 (Disk Digital files)
  - Church Women United Awards/Luncheon - C.W.U: Perfect 2010, 2010/10/23 (Binder 21)
  - Church Women United Awards/Luncheon - C.W.U: Perfect 2010, 2010/10/23 (Disk Digital files)
  - Ophellia and Frank Perry 50th Wedding Anniversary, 2011/01/16 (Binder 13)
  - Ophellia and Frank Perry 50th Wedding Anniversary, 2011/01/16 (Disk Digital files)
  - Laura Edwards 70th Birthday Celebration, 2011/03/26 (Binder 24)
  - Laura Edwards 70th Birthday Celebration, 2011/03/26 (Disk Digital files)
  - Donna Kirton 50th Birthday Celebration, 2011/03/27 (Binder 24)
  - Donna Kirton 50th Birthday Celebration, 2011/03/27 (Disk Digital files)
  - Tuskegee Airmen - C. Govam Chapter, 2011/05/21 (Binder 21)
  - Tuskegee Airmen - C. Govam Chapter, 2011/05/21 (Disk Digital files)
  - Clive Oscar sang - Grand Master (Mechanics Grand Lodge), 2011/05/07 and 2011/07 (Binder 21)
  - Clive Oscar sang - Grand Master (Mechanics Grand Lodge), 2011/05/07 and 2011/07 (Disk Digital files)
  - George Irving 100th Birthday celebration, 2011/06/12 (Binder 21)
  - George Irving 100th Birthday celebration, 2011/06/12 (Disk Digital files)
  - Alvin and Judith King, 2011/08/28 (Binder 21)
  - Alvin and Judith King, 2011/08/28 (Disk Digital files)
  - Cornerstone Baptist Church Business and Professional Women awards luncheon, 2011/09/24 (Binder 24)
  - Cornerstone Baptist Church Business and Professional Women awards luncheon, 2011/09/24 (Disk Digital files)
  - Frank McGibbon prints and proofs, 2011/10/22 (Binder 24)
  - Frank McGibbon prints and proofs, 2011/10/22 (Disk Digital files)
- Series 2: Business records, 1960s-2008; 0.4 Linear Feet in one manuscript box
  The series contains a small assortment of records relating to Wilson's commercial photography business, dating from the 1960s to 2008. It also includes records relating to his pension and welfare funds as a member of the Graphic Communications International Union Local 119B.
  - Supreme Printing Co. and SETAB brochures, 1960s (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Promotional prints, 1968-1987 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Business records, 1975-1988 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Business card, circa 1980s (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Graphic Communications International Union Local 119B, New York pension and welfare funds, 1984-2007 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Family groups proof/samples, 1998 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Computer class - Cathedral Adult Education School, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Photoshop notes, 2003-2004 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Dale and Susan thank you for making our 25th Anniversary celebration special (Audio DVD), 2008 (Box 31, Folder 12)
- Series 3: Personal photographs, circa 1920s-2010; 1 Linear Feet in three binders, one manuscript box, and one half manuscript box; 0.379 Gigabytes in 172 files
  The series contains photographs of Wilson's family and friends, dating from circa 1920s to 2010. It includes photographic negatives, prints, transparencies, and Polaroids. The bulk of the photographs document his immediate family: his wife Marie, son Sidney, and daughter Susan. Marie's work as a quilter and bag maker is well documented in the series. Of particular note are images of the "Weaver of Dreams" quilt that was featured at the Martin Luther King Jr. Center for Nonviolent Social Change. Wilson's passion for the outdoors is also well documented. This includes fishing trips, such as local outings to Sheepshead Bay and Jamaica Bay, as well as trips to New England and North Carolina. It also includes photographs documenting trips to Medusa, New York and rifle shooting. Finally, the series includes photographs documenting Wilson's trip with other Tuskegee Airmen to President Barack Obama's inauguration in January 2009.
  - Family and others, circa 1920s-2000 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Fishing, 1943-1995 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Theobald, family, and friends, 1952-1984 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Sidney and Susan B. Wilson (up til 1958), circa 1940s-1950s (Binder 27)
  - Dorothy and Mavis baby pics (up til 1958), 1950s (Binder 27)
  - Nantucket, Massachusetts, and Chicago, 1951-1958 (Binder 28)
  - People Miscellaneous: Joe Beanstock, Bruno and Thrumpet, Jame Cerboni, Joe Cardone, Frank and Ralph the Butchers, George Della Lotta, Sam Palmer, George (bartender at Joe Maxwells), Gwendolyn Collins, Rita Palmer, Amy Samuels, 1957-1961 (Binder 27)
  - PS 94, circa 1950s-1960s (Binder 28)
  - Wilbur Boyce and family, Sis and Buster Dennis, Haines Falls (NY), Hattie and Taylor, Auto wreck, Wilbur Sr., Edith and Cats, House at Medusa, Vogal and son, 1959-1970 (Binder 27)
  - Susan and friends, 1959-1976 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Marie, kids, and friends, 1959-1984 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Sidney, Susan, and friends, 1950s-1976 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Family, circa 1950s-2000s (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - 646 Eastern Parkway, circa 1960s (Binder 27)
  - Capt.'s Play, circa 1960s (Binder 28)
  - Fire and inside automobile, circa 1960s (Binder 28)
  - Local Union #119: Bob McCrindle, Artie Grossman, Joe Hellman, Steve Oberski, Joe McKenna, Dorothy Cannon, Joe Ash, Charles Novara, circa 1960s (Binder 27)
  - Personal photographs: Coney Island, waterfront, street scenes, zoo, buildings, fire, circa 1960s (Binder 27)
  - Tall ship in harbor, circa 1960s (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Zola and Manny (two children), circa 1960s (Binder 27)
  - John and Daisy Banner party, 1960 (Binder 28)
  - Thomas and Rebecca Campbell's wedding, circa 1961 (Binder 28)
  - Thomas and Rebecca Campbell's son, 1962 (Binder 28)
  - Imperial Diplomats S.C., 1963 (Binder 28)
  - Victor and Dorothy Knight and family (Army and Easter), 1964-1968 (Binder 27)
  - Grady and Pam Sharp, and family, 1965-1966 (Binder 28)
  - Medusa - Roger-Wilhamewn (?), Edith, Marie, etc., 1966 (Binder 28)
  - Alfred Bailey and family, 1967-1980 (Binder 28)
  - Leroy Preston, Girls Club, etc., 1960s-1971 (Binder 28)
  - Esther Burgess?, 1960s-circa 1990s (Binder 28)
  - Theobald Wilson ID photographs, 1973-1981 (Binder 29)
  - Capt. Preston, 1976 (Binder 28)
  - Capt.'s Cat - Calidonia, 1977 (Binder 28)
  - Thomas Knight and family, 1977 (Binder 28)
  - Wee Wee's Grandma (copy of old photograph), 1977 (Binder 27)
  - Marie's bags, 1977-1987 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Experimental photographs?, circa 1970s-1990s (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Personal Polaroids, 1970s-2003 (Box Polaroid box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1980s (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Armite and Grady Sharp, 1980 (Binder 28)
  - 250 Grove Avenue, Metuchen, NJ, 1981/08/15 (Binder 29)
  - Maggie and Grady Sharp, 1982 (Binder 28)
  - Martin Luther King "Weaver of Dreams" Quilt, 1986/01/14 (Binder 16)
  - Visit to Wes and Susan, Sid and Claudia, Cydnie and Thea, 1989 (Binder 29)
  - Street/subway photography and Marie's "first assignment", circa 1990s (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Women of Color Quilters Network, 1992-1993 (Binder 8)
  - Tuskegee Airmen - President Barack Obama inauguration, Washington DC, 2009/01/20 (Binder 26)
  - Tuskegee Airmen - President Barack Obama inauguration, Washington DC, 2009/01/20 (Disk Digital files)
  - Wes-Sue-Roy Van Norton, Visit Granddad for Father's Day, 2010/06/17 (Binder 24)
  - Wes-Sue-Roy Van Norton, Visit Granddad for Father's Day, 2010/06/17 (Disk Digital files)
- Series 4: Personal papers, 1918-2011; 0.3 Linear Feet in eight folders
  The series contains a small assortment of personal papers that belonged to Wilson, dating from 1918 to 2011. They include records relating to his wife's family (the Dowells), passports and other licenses, a record of a burglary of his home at 199 Lincoln Road, 84 Ross Street housing records, and papers relating to the Tuskegee Airmen.
  - Dowell family records, 1918-1991 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Passports, licenses, medical appointment cards, etc., 1923-1980s (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - The Sultan Social Club annual fall dance program, 1939 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Du Sable High School invitation, 1940 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - 199 Lincoln Road burglary report and photographs, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - 84 Ross Street housing records, 2005-2007 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Tuskegee Airmen (two folders), 1998-2011 (Box 31, Folder 2-3)
- Series 5: Photography equipment, circa 1950s-2000s; 4 Linear Feet in fours boxes and one folder
  The items in this series are not arranged in any particular order.
  The series contains photography equipment and related items used by Wilson, dating from circa 1950s to the 2000s.
  - Beire Beirette 35mm camera with case, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 35)
  - Polaroid Land Camera Model 95A, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 35)
  - Polaroid 195 camera, circa 1970s (Box 35)
  - Bell & Howell One-Nine 8mm movie camera, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 35)
  - Large format developing tanks (3 items), circa 1960s-1990s (Box 34)
  - Lens and mounts (10 items), circa 1960s-1990s (Box 36)
  - Lens mount, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 35)
  - Gossen Luna Pro light meter with case, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 35)
  - Film loaders (2 items), circa 1960s-1980s (Box 35)
  - Cords (2 items), circa 1960s-1990s (Box 35)
  - Dark room timer, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 34)
  - Developing chemicals (6 items), circa 1960s-1990s (Box 33)
  - Kodak Plus-X pan film, 1990s (Box 33)
  - Kodak Portra film (NC and VC) (3 items), 2000s (Box 36)
  - Color separation guides and sensitivity guide, circa 1960s, 1978 (Box 32, Folder 9)